The world's most famous cat and mouse in their first motion picture.
Tom and Jerry: The Movie is a animation, comedy,
family film directed by Phil Roman.
The popular cartoon cat and mouse are thrown into a feature film.
The story has the twosome trying to help an orphan girl who is
being berated and exploited by a greedy guardian.
Tom (voice), played by Richard Kind.
Jerry (voice), played by Dana Hill.
Robyn Starling (voice), played by Anndi McAfee.
Lickboot (voice), played by Tony Jay.
Captain Kiddie (voice), played by Rip Taylor.
Doctor Applecheek (voice), played by Henry Gibson.
Tom and Jerry: The Movie is a 1992 American animated musical comedy film based on the
characters Tom and Jerry created by William Hanna and Joseph Barbera.
It was produced and directed by Phil Roman, with a screenplay written by Dennis Marks, who
also scripted some episodes of the then-airing TV series Tom & Jerry Kids.
It features original songs written by Henry Mancini and Leslie
Bricusse and a score also composed by Mancini.
The film stars the voices of Richard Kind, Dana Hill, Anndi McAfee, Tony Jay,
Rip Taylor, Henry Gibson, Michael Bell, Ed Gilbert, David L.
Lander, Howard Morris, and Charlotte Rae.
It is the very first theatrical feature-length animated film featuring the titular characters, as
well as the first piece of theatrically released Tom and Jerry media in 25 years.
Although largely mute in the original cartoons, Tom and Jerry are given
extensive spoken dialogue for the only time to date.
Joseph Barbera, co-founder of Hanna-Barbera Productions and co-creator of the original
Tom and Jerry short films, served as the film's creative consultant.
The film tells the story about an eight-year-old girl named Robyn Starling, who enlists Tom and Jerry's help
to escape from her evil legal guardian and reunite with her lost and presumed-dead father.
Following its premiere in Germany on October 1, 1992, Tom and Jerry: The Movie was released theatrically in the United
States on July 30, 1993, by Miramax Films, which was a subsidiary of The Walt Disney Company at the time.
The film grossed $3.6 million and received negative reviews.
The film explores themes of villain, cartoon cat,
family, cartoon mouse, female villain.
The tone is lighthearted.